How have you seen the evolution of the Bitcoin miners from those early days to now?
Yeah, I mean, when I joined Bitfuri, the whole ecosystem was one petahash.
So it was very, very early. And what we've seen over the years, the progression towards
institutionalization of the space. Whereas before, it would be $20-30 million to tape out a chip
to build a data center. Now you're talking about billions of dollars.
And in this journey, we mined hundreds of thousands of Bitcoins, and we incubated two mining companies
that are listed on the NASDAQ, and they are going in and raising billions of dollars.
So I was privileged to be at the forefront of evolution from early on to today where we are.
One question I often wonder when it comes to Bitcoin mining is we're seeing more and more state
nations start mining as well. We saw with Bhutan, with single Salvador, and many others.
Do you believe that's kind of unfair competition one day with the privately-owned or listed mining
companies, the fact that these state nations are coming into the space? The beauty of Bitcoin,
it's an open source. And you can mine as a private organization, as a government,
and more there are entities that are mining, whether it's government or the enterprises,
or decentralized in networking. So we welcome it, and actually we've been
orange-pilling, as you know, a term of talking people about the benefits of Bitcoin and many
governments. So we're glad that that is taking the place, and many more are about to join.
So talking about the evolution of miners, we've seen many miners over the last two or three years
switch to AI, actually. Do you believe that is just a transient trend, or do you believe we'll have
the AI and Bitcoin miners quabitate for the first few future? Absolutely. There is no coincidence
in terms of the switch, because if you're going to Bitcoin mining is a high-performance computing
exercise, in terms of putting all the components together. And Bitfury, actually, from a very getgo,
was looking as AI as one of the ways to diversify. And that's why, in 2020, we spun out a team of
chip designers to do an AI chip design, and they have one of the leading European AI chip
companies called Excelera. But Cypher and Hot Aid, all of the companies we incubate in going to AI,
is just an extension of Bitcoin mining. So I see a very natural extension of that.
So, you know, Georgia, I think we've had both the privilege of being in the space for many
years, and you just published a book called "And Then You Win." How do you see founders in the crypto
space being different from founders and other industries? And do you believe what anybody is
looking at launching a crypto-related business? What attributes do you need to have to succeed
in this space? Resilience. Resilience and resilience, because this is the industry which we were
laughed at. We were ignored at. There was a massive fight in terms of going on. And now we're seeing
that there is this victory coming in terms of success and in terms of harvesting the capital.
You need to have resilience. You need to have adaptability. And you need to come to this industry
with an idea to make a world a better place. So I see a lot of Bitcoiners early investors that
came in that are investing now a lot of capital for doing good and making a positive impact and
privileged to be part of the journey. And we first came. Bitcoin was $400, and we've seen the progression
of adoption and accumulation. And we're very privileged. We are a big fans of UAE, and we look
to double down around investments and continue to be partnership here.
So, George, over the last dozen years or so, obviously, there's been a lot of challenges
the crypto industry has faced and has overcome in most cases. What are the challenges you're
the most worried about for the next decade as you look at the future outlook of the industry?
I think the biggest challenge is to become complacent, to think that we have already won,
and the kind of battle is over. But no, we need to double down in terms of our investments,
investments in education, investments on technology, scaling Bitcoin, supporting various ecosystems
around it. So we're still in early innings of this exciting journey. And also interesting to see
how Bitcoin and crypto will overlap with AI and the impact that's going to have on a society,
so very exciting 20 years ahead of us. What's your view on, let's say, education, for example?
Do you believe the crypto industry, and, you know, does enough to help bring forward the
cause of crypto education, or what do you think should be done to bring forward this topic?
I think the biggest problem, what I'm seeing right now is that there's so much technological
advancement happening in the world, but the human consciousness is not keeping up with that,
and there is a big gap. So there needs to be really an education in doubling down on family
values, on doing good, making a positive impact, and it really starts with the family. So if we
focus on that on education of a consciousness of a humanity where we're going to embrace this
great technology that is coming, it's really vital. Otherwise, we're going to be in a big mess.
Very philosophical stance there. Before I let you go, you mentioned about the future of Bitcoin.
Price prediction, one year and five year from now, when it comes to Bitcoin, how do you see the asset
class of all? Oh, Henry, I've been an old timer. So when Bitcoin was 100, I was telling anyone it
would go to 10,000. When it was 1,000 to 100,000. So we're at 100,000 now. It's for surely going to
1 million within the next five years. Probability is 99%. And the reason is very simple. The reason
is as long as central banks continue printing the money, as long as the global governments
continue running massive budget deficits, Bitcoin is a directional bet upwards. That's it.
Doward George, the Kickstarter co-founder of Bitfury.